《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
看到他和她在一起那样
Gives me the creeps
让我背脊发凉
seeing him acting like that with her...
我们的人怎么能被她们迷住呢
How can one of us get that roped in by one of them?
听我说  上士
Look, Chief,
我知道她对你的感觉 她爱你
I know how she felt about you. She loved you.
我也许该感激你
You know what, I should probably be grateful to you.
因为她肚子里的那个怪物可能就是我的了
Because that freak in her belly could've been mine.
你还记得
Do you have actual memories
在赛昂人袭击之前你和上士的事么
of being with the Chief before the Cylon attack?
你是我的孩子的父亲 你在我心中的位置是第一位的
You're the father of my child. You're the first in my heart.
任何事都不会改变这些事实
And nothing is ever gonna change that.
好了  是这样的
All right, here's the deal.
我们要造一架新型战机
We are gonna build a new fighter.
黑鸟  试飞  准许发射
Blackbird test flight, cleared for launch.
卡拉狄加  我是阿波罗 我找不到她了
Galactica, Apollo. I've lost her.
你当然找不到了 这是一架该死的隐型战机  还记得么
Of course, you lost contact. It's a damn stealth ship, remember?
抵抗组织的基地在这里
The resistance base camp is here.
在该区域唯一的赛昂机场以北300公里
Three hundred clicks north of the only Cylon airbase in the area.
我们可以通过马托克峡谷直接空降7架猛禽
We can drop seven Raptors straight down through the Martok Valley
在赛昂派出战机前就能往返
and be in and out before the Cylons have a chance to launch their Raiders.
猛禽带抵抗战士返回卡拉狄加后
The Raptors return the Galactica
我们就立刻跳离那该死的地方
with the resistance fighters, we jump the hell out of there.
很简单
Simple.
那舰队呢
Where's the Fleet?
舰队就停在此地
The Fleet will remain here.
我会指派7架蝮蛇和1架猛禽护卫
I've tasked seven Vipers and one Raptor to stay with them.
7架蝮蛇？
Seven Vipers?
还有1架猛禽
And one Raptor.
中尉
Lieutenant,
卡拉狄加到卡布里卡
how many jumps
一共要跳跃多少次
will it take Galactica to reach Caprica?
241次
241.
241次？
241?
保守估计
That's conservative.
你知道的
And you know it.
一旦跳过红线
Once you jump the Red Line,
导航系统会在每次
navigational error creeps into
跳跃运算中出现偏差
every single jump calculation that you make.
有可能要花2倍的次数
It could take us twice that amount of time
才能找到卡布里拉登陆
to actually find Caprica, let alone land.
我明白其中的风险
I understand the risks.
真的吗？
ADAMA: Do you really?
我们得试试
We have to try.
中尉 我很尊重你所做的努力
Lieutenant, I respect what you're trying to do here.
可是…
However...
我们要对舰队里的其他人负责
We have a duty to the people we left behind.
我明白
I understand that.
我们必须找到跳回卡布里卡的路线并…
We have to find a way to jump back to Caprica and go get the...
卡拉
Kara.
各就各位  各就各位
GAETA: Action stations, action stations. Set Condition One throughout the ship.
这不是演习  重复  各就各位  各就各位
This is not a drill. Repeat. Action stations, action stations.
全船一级戒备
Set Condition One throughout the ship.
总统女士
ADAMA: Well, Madam President,
看来今天的参观要泡汤了
looks like you picked a hell of a day for a visit.
我是指挥官  现况报告
This is the commander. Sitrep.
不明飞船刚跳进雷达监视范围  方位不变  范围递减
Bogey just jumped into dradis range, CBDR.
从大小来看可能是一艘赛昂基地飞船
From the size of it, it's probably a Cylon base ship.
巡逻机正前去截击
CAP's on its way to intercept.
通知舰队进行紧急跳跃
Alert the Fleet to an emergency jump.
我和总统这就过去
I'm on my way with the President.
卡拉狄加  我是阿波罗 我在飞往基地之星的路上
Galactica, Apollo, I'm outbound on course to the Base Star.
小凯与我同行
Tag alongside me.
预计1分钟后将进行拦截
I estimate one minute till I intercept.
收到  阿波罗
DUALLA: Roger that, Apollo.
报告  待战机已经出发
Be advised, alert fighters have launched
3分钟内将在你的6点钟方向出现
and will take station on your six in three minutes.
军情报告
Sitrep.
待战机已经出发
Alert fighters have launched.
雷达发现新目标 他们派出了突袭机
New dradis contact, they're launching Raiders.
我们还要多久才能跳跃?
How long till we jump?
还得2分钟
Another two minutes.
长官...
Sir?
长官  我收到的是殖民舰队的应答信号
Sir, I'm getting Colonial transponders.
殖民舰队?
Colonial?
靠  他们现在要用我们自己的信号来对付我们了
Hell, now they're using our own signals against us.
也许吧
Maybe.
不要开火 暂停跳跃
Weapons hold. Hold the jump, too.
我想你是有什么打算吧?
Something up your sleeve, I take it?
各船  这里是卡拉狄加  暂停跳跃
All ships, Galactica, hold jump.
再说一次  暂停跳跃
Say again, hold jump.
船对船 殖民舰队1号优先频道
Ship to ship, Colonial priority one channel.
发送敌方挑战信号和身份
Send hostile challenge and ID.
然后把答复接到扬声器上
And put your reply up on the speakers.
注意  未知飞船
DUALLA: Attention, unknown vessel.
这里是太空堡垒卡拉狄加
This is the Battlestar Galactica.
表明身份  否则我们将攻击你们
Identify yourself or we will fire upon you.
现在的范围是1700  长官
Range now 1,700, sir.
这里是太空堡垒帕伽索斯
MAN: This is the Battlestar Pegasus
与声称是太空堡垒舰队的飞船通话 请回答
to the ship claiming to be the Galactica. Please respond.
帕伽索斯  怎么可能?
Pegasus? How could that be?
他们的整个舰队已经被摧毁了
The entire fleet was destroyed.
让我直接通话
Give me direct contact.
帕伽索斯  我是卡拉狄加的指挥官
Pegasus, this is Galactica actual.
立即出示识别码证明身份
Authenticate identity with recognition codes immediately.
长官...
Sir.
我收到了殖民舰队的识别码
I'm receiving Colonial recognition codes.
是真的
They're authentic.
卡拉狄加  我是帕伽索斯的指挥官
CAIN: Galactica, this is Pegasus actual.
阿达玛  是你吗?
Adama, is that you?
凯恩上将
Admiral Cain.
听到你的声音真是荣幸
What a pleasure to hear your voice.
退出战斗状态
Disengage.
红队  退出战斗状态 红队  退出战斗状态
Red Team, disengage. Red Team, disengage.
指挥官
CAIN: Commander,
我不知道说什么好了
I don't know what to say.
这是一个奇迹
This is a miracle.
你说出了我要说的话
You took the words right out of my mouth.
全体舰队解除一级戒备
Step down to Condition One throughout the Fleet.
卡拉狄加  我是阿波罗 你不会相信…
Galactica Apollo, you are not going to believe
我从外面看她的样子
what I'm looking at out here.
像是在做梦
It's like a dream.
确实是一场梦
It is a dream.
帕伽索斯猛禽861号 这里是卡拉狄加
MAN:Pegasus Raptor 861, Galactica.
放下滑轨  锁定磁力    欢迎登舰  上将
Skids down, mag secure. Welcome aboard, Admiral.
就像是你所读的幸运之事
TIGH: This is a stroke of luck like you read about.
我们也该有点好运了
We could use a little luck right now.
无可厚非
Can't argue that.
你认识这个凯恩上将吗?
You know this Admiral Cain?
只是听说过
Only heard about her.
不过她是晋升很快的年轻军官
But she's a very young officer on a very fast track.
足智多谋
She's very smart.
坚韧强硬
Very tough.
家世显赫
Very well-connected.
她当时淘汰了名单上大半的指挥官
Fleet promoted her to rear admiral
被舰队授予少将军衔
over half the commanders on the list.
这是什么玩意？开派对么
TIGH: What the hell is this, a party?
不好意思 长官
CALLY: Sorry, sir.
甲板清空
All clear the deck.
上校 算了 这是个伟大的时刻
Oh, Colonel, let it go. It's a big moment. Come on.
像个军人样  各位!
Get into ranks, people!
精神点儿!  这不是休息
Look sharp. This isn't recess!
快  陆战队来了  军容整洁点儿
Come on, the landing party is here. Dress and cover.
真庆幸你出现了  不能来得太早
Nice of you to show up. Couldn't get here too early.
士兵!  立正!
Group, attention!
凯恩上将  欢迎来到卡拉狄加
Admiral Cain, welcome aboard the Galactica.
阿达玛指挥官
Commander Adama,
荣幸至致
it's an honor.
上校 让大家稍息
Colonel, put your men at ease.
稍息
At ease.
允许我向你引见殖民地总统劳拉·罗丝琳
Allow me to present to you the President of the Colonies, Laura Roslin.
说来话长     欢迎
It's a long story. Welcome.
总统女士  幸会
Madam President, pleasure.
波塔尔博士？
Dr. Baltar?
是
Yes.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
我仅代表帕伽索斯的军官和船员
On behalf of the officers and the crew of the Pegasus,
对于见到各位感到非常荣幸
it's a pleasure to see all of you.
欢迎回归殖民舰队
Welcome back to the Colonial Fleet.
泰勒上尉
Captain Taylor.
卡拉·瑟瑞丝  泰勒上尉
Kara Thrace. Captain Taylor.
很抱歉
Sorry about all of this.
不 很高兴见到你
No, it's so good to see you.
为12殖民地
To the 12 Colonies.
很高兴你们登舰
It's good to have you aboard.
好东西
Good stuff.
我最后的存货了
One of my last bottles.
上将
Admiral.
我急切地想问一些问题
I'm fairly burning with questions.
希望你不要介意我的唐突
I hope you don't mind if I just dive in.
请讲  你们是怎么找到我们的?
Please. How did you find us?
我们当时在跟踪一支赛昂舰队...
Well, we were tracking a Cylon fleet.
最初我们试图预测他们的行踪
We were trying to predict their movements,
那另人捉摸不定
which seemed rather random initially.
直到我们发现他们只是跳跃到具有天然资源的星系
Until we realized that they were just jumping to systems with natural resources.
所以我们就开始亲自勘察那些星系...
So, we began to scout those systems ourselves,
希望可以实行打完就跑的战术 来打击他们的舰队
hoping to carry out hit-and-run attacks on their fleet.
但没找到赛昂人  却找到了你们
But instead of finding the Cylons, we found you.
就是说你们一直在攻击他们的舰队?
So, you've been attacking their fleet?
你也知道什么是最好的防守吧
Well, you know what they say about the best defense.
嗯
Hmm.
你们怎么躲过赛昂人对殖民地的初次攻击的?
How did you avoid the initial Cylon attack on the Colonies?
你不介意的话  我再来一杯
I'll have another if you don't mind.
卡拉狄加上的最好喝了
Galactica's finest.
这比一次生动的内部参观爽多了  谢谢
Beats the hell out of the nickel tour. Thank you.
如果你已经看过一艘老式的太空堡垒 其他的就都一样了
I figured if you'd seen one old Battlestar, you'd seen them all.
恩  她确实是过时了
Yeah, well, she's an old one.
想不到赛昂人居然没把你们
I can't believe the Cylons didn't kick your ass
这大铁牛打个七零八落啊
up one side and down the other in this bucket.
不好意思
Sorry.
不好意思 除了你没人能轻慢这艘船
I'm sorry. No one gets to insult your ship except you.
他妈的没错
You're Gods damn right.
冲着你这句话...
And just for that
这次不给你喝了
you have to skip this round.
我们当时正停泊在天蝎舰队的船坞
We were docking at Scorpion Fleet Shipyard.
准备进行为期3个月的大修
We were getting ready to go in for a three-month overhaul.
大部分船员已经准备好去休长假或与家人重聚
Most of the crew was getting ready for extended shore leave and family reunions.
船上由副长负责
XO had the deck.
我在自己的寝室里  整理一些书面文件
I was down in my quarters, wrapping up some paperwork
准备打包回家去塔诺朗
and getting ready to pack up to go home to Tauron.
就在这时赛昂人攻击了
And that's when the Cylons attacked.
他们用3颗  也许是4颗核弹打击了船坞
They hit the shipyard with three, maybe four nukes.
5艘船  其中2艘是太空堡垒
Five ships. Two of them Battlestars.
当场就被摧毁了
They were destroyed right there.
很幸运的是…
And luckily, very luckily,
爆炸的冲击波让赛昂的雷达也失效了
the blast blinded the Cylon dradis.
所以他们没发现我们还未被摧毁
So they were unable to determine that we were still intact.
但是发射舱内
But there were... There were explosions,
还是发生了爆炸和火灾
and fires in the launch bays,
燃料和军械库也着火了
and fuel and ordnance igniting,
人们惊慌失措
people screaming.
等我回到作战信息中心的时候...
And by the time I got back to CIC,
我发现我已经损失了700人
I discovered that I'd lost over 700 men.
我的天
My Gods.
我们当时毫无防备 所以我下令进行跳跃
We were completely defenseless, so I ordered a jump.
跳到哪里?
To where?
哪里都行
Wherever.
跳到哪儿算哪儿  能跳跃就行
Nowhere. Just jump.
盲目地跳跃
ADAMA: Blind jump.
不一定跳到什么地方  靠直觉了
Could've ended up anywhere. Gutsy call.
恩  绝望之举
No. Desperate move.
看不出还有什么选择
Didn't see any other choice.
你们怎么躲过赛昂对计算机系统的渗透的
How'd you avoid the Cylons infiltrating your computer system?
为了大修 我们的计算系系统全部离线了
Well, our networks were off-line in preparation for the overhaul.
是啊 帕伽索斯一直都是幸运之舰
Yes, Pegasus has always been a rather lucky ship.
为了幸运之舰
To lucky ships.
我相信你的故事
I'm sure you have
一定很曲折
quite a story to tell as well.
但我不会要求你现在立即讲给我听
But I won't make you go through it right this very minute.
等你有机会的话 可以把你的日志送到我这里来
You can send up your logs when you get the chance.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
有什么不妥么?
CAIN: Is something wrong?
没什么
No.
我有时就忘了军队的规矩了
I sometimes forget about the rules of military protocol.
凯恩上将是我的上级军官
ADAMA: Admiral Cain is my superior officer.
她将拥有整个舰队的指挥权
She will take complete command of the entire Fleet.
我还在想怎么开口提这事
I was wondering how to broach that topic.
相信我
Trust me when I say
当我说严格的等级制度的时候是无意的
that while the chain of command is strict, it is not heartless.
我也是无心的
And neither am I.
这是你的船
This is your ship.
我无意介入卡拉狄加的内政
And I have no desire to interfere with Galactica's internal affairs.
谢谢你  上将
I appreciate it, Admiral.
总统女士  你的表情好象我欠你很多钱一样
Madam President, you look like I just shot your dog.
不  只是--
No, I just...
只是指挥官和我们经历了太多
Just the Commander and I, we've been through a lot.
打扰了    总统女士?
Excuse me. Madam President?
两位  我失陪一下
If you'll both excuse me.
上将  我们说不尽多么感激你来到这里
Admiral, I can't tell you how grateful we are to have you here.
谢谢你找到了我们
Thank you for finding us.
总统女士
Madam President.
教育部长?
The Secretary of Education?
她一路走来不容易
She's come a long way.
我想是的
I'm sure.
和我说说凯恩上将
So tell me about Admiral Cain.
军官的谨慎(守口如瓶)?
Officer's discretion.
当然
Of course.
我们追踪一支我们本以为是赛昂人的通讯队
We were going after what we thought was a little Cylon comm relay.
小菜一碟  对吧?
Easy target, right?
结果根本不是通讯队
Turns out it wasn't a comm relay at all. It was a staging area
而是15支突袭机编队的集结地
full of 15 squadrons of Raiders.
凯恩上将命令我们的副长发动攻击
Admiral Cain ordered our XO to attack.
那俩人关系非常好
Those two were real close.
他已经为她效力几年了
He'd served with her for years.
但是事情就出在这儿
But here's the thing.
他拒绝执行命令
He refused the order.
不可能吧
No frakking way.
还有个问题
There's one other matter.
我们的船上有一个赛昂囚犯
We have a Cylon prisoner aboard this ship.
真的?
Really?
我们的船上也有一个
We have one on ours as well.
我们的那个经验证是一个良好的情报源
Ours has proven to be an excellent source of intelligence.
她一直非常合作
She's been very cooperative.
副总统波塔尔博士一直在与她接触
The Vice President, Dr. Baltar, has been working with her.
他能在舰上是你们的幸运
You're very lucky to have him onboard.
很幸运
Very lucky.
她怎么做了?
TIGH: What did she do?
她让他交出枪
She asked for his gun.
当着全体船员的面打爆了他的头
Shot him in the head with it in front of the whole crew.
然后她转向我
And then she turned to me.
你怎么做了?
What did you do?
我下令发动攻击 你说我能怎么做?
Then I ordered the frakking attack, what do you think I did?
没那回事
No.
没那回事  我在开玩笑
No, no. I'm just joking.
开玩笑的
I'm just kidding, you know.
嗯？
Huh?
没有
No, no.
嗨
Hey.
再来些  好吗？
Set us up again, will you?
我们还没能从我们的赛昂那得到任何有用的信息
We haven't been able to get anything useful out of our Cylon.
我希望能尽快安排和波塔尔博士见面
I'd like to set up an appointment with Dr. Baltar as soon as possible.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
掌握指挥权 我也是不乐意而为之 比尔
It gives me no pleasure to have to take command, Bill.
这你要知道
I want you to know that.
别那么想  上将
Don't give it a moment's thought, Admiral.
这是记分卡吗?
Is this a scorecard?
你们用船的一边当记分卡?
You guys put scorecards on the side of your ships?
好象你不记分似的
Like you don't keep score.
我可不会把分数涂在船的一边
You don't see me painting them on the side
好象在对全宇宙吹嘘一样
like I'm bragging to the whole frakking universe.
那上面可显示杀敌48架
That's 48 kills right there.
特别嘛  你们还拿帽子和T恤(当纪念品)吗?
That's special. Do you have caps and T-shirts, too?
哪位是卡拉狄加的空军指挥官?
Where's the Galactica CAG?
我就是
Right here.
让我听一下你的飞行编队的总结  上尉
Let's hear the rundown on this squadron of yours, Captain.
我看你对你的杀敌数不做记录  该开始做记录了
I see you don't keep track of your kills. You should start.
激励斗志  大家竞赛  体现团队精神
Encourages morale, gets the competition going, esprit de corps.
这倒是一种哲学
Well, that's one philosophy.
这是凯恩上将的哲学
It's Admiral Cain's philosophy.
也就意味着从现在开始是你的哲学  上尉
That means it's your philosophy now, Captain.
我指挥官的名字是阿达玛
The name of my commander is Adama.
应该容易记住吧  因为那是我的名字
It should be pretty easy to remember, 'cause it's my name.
恩
Yeah.
我会记住的  爸爸的乖宝宝
I'll keep that in mind, daddy's boy.
走去看一下你的武器清单
Let's see your ordnance lists.
我永远也无法适应他们人性化的样子
I can never get over how human they look.
不可思议 对吗
Yes. It's uncanny, isn't it?
这个赛昂帮了我们大忙
This model has been very useful, in fact.
它让我们对赛昂的…
It's given us key insights into
信息系统 战略战术计划有了深入了解
Cylon information systems, tactics, strategic plans.
我在我们和另一艘殖民地战舰遭遇时获得的
I take it we've encountered another Colonial warship.
你们没用刑就得到了这些？
You've gotten all of this intel without coercion?
是的
BALTAR: Oh, yes.
我发现
I find the application
用强迫性的逼供手段会适得其反
of physical or coercive techniques to be counter-productive.
你当我不存在
You're going to ignore me.
好像我不会说话一样
Pretend I can't speak.
我们像对待人类一样对待她
We treat this model as if it's the human being it pretends to be.
这使得她愿意合作
That seems to make it more cooperative.
我还没向您展示实验室吧？
BALTAR: I haven't shown you the lab, have I?
由于我的生理学和计算机编程方面的背景
So with the background in physics, and computer programming,
他们让我主持赛昂人的项目
they made me head of the Cylon branch
我主要致力于赛昂人辩识方面
and my main focus is on Cylon detection.
我们有自己的赛昂囚犯
We have our own Cylon prisoner.
我想让你尽快去检查它
I'd like you to examine it as soon as possible.
看是否能从它那里发现什么
See if you can glean anything from it.
我倒想知道那个赛昂人是谁
I wonder who the Cylon will turn out to be?
陌生人?  熟面孔?
A stranger, a familiar face,
值得信赖的朋友转瞬之间就成了敌人?
a trusted friend who suddenly turns out to be the enemy?
你听到我说什么了么?
Did you hear what I just said?
是的  是的
Yes, yes.
我真的...我很乐意去检查那个犯人
I'd be really... I'd be very happy to examine the prisoner.
指挥官
Commander.
上将  上将  真不好意思
Admiral. Admiral. I am so sorry.
我们从它那里还一无所获
We haven't been able to get anything useful out of it.
或许你的运气会好些
Perhaps you'll have better luck.
她不好对付 不是吗
She's a hard case, isn't she?
正是你喜欢的类型 盖尤斯
Just your type, Gaius.
你对女强人型的情有独钟
You do have a thing for strong, powerful women.
是 没错
Yes, I do.
我尽力而为 长官
I'll do my best, sir.
听起来  你俩都喝醉了
Sounds like you were both drunk.
无庸质疑
TIGH: No question.
但他不是在说谎 这我可以向你保证
But he wasn't lying. I can tell you that right now.
我希望你不要忙下定论
Well, I hope you won't jump to conclusions.
等有了证据再说
Wait for all the facts.
局势重要
Context matters.
局势?
Context?
那女人当着全体船员的面杀死了一名军官
That woman shot an officer right in front of the crew.
我们击落了一整艘...
We shot down an entire civilian transport
载有上千人的民用运输船
with over a thousand people onboard.
就在这里写着
Says so right there.
完全是两码事
That was completely different.
况且我们不了解那艘船上的人
And we don't know there were people on that ship.
所以我才希望
Which is why I hope
上将能够读完全部日志
the Admiral reads the complete log
了解当前的形势
and understands the context.
我们应该向凯恩上将要她的日志
We should ask Admiral Cain for her logs.
这样才能了解她的状态
Just so we can put her in context.
那倒好了
Wouldn't that be nice.
凯莉 扳手
TYROL: Cally, get a wrench.
谢谢
Thanks.
上士 快看这个
Chief. Chief, take a look at this.
这些是备件？
Are these spare parts?
谨致在卡拉狄加的飞行甲板组同僚
"For our fellow knuckledraggers on the Galactica.
帕伽索斯甲板组敬上
"Courtesy of the Pegasus Deck Gang. "
凯莉 我开始喜欢那艘船了
Cally, I'm starting to like that ship.
中尉
Lieutenant.
费雷利中尉
Lieutenant Ferelli.
这些是导航系统升级软件
These are navigational updates,
软件补丁还有系统升级软件
software patches and systems upgrades.
这是帕伽索斯上完整的数字图书馆资料
And this is the complete Pegasus on-board digital library.
殖民地卷宗里关于查莱克审判的…
Everything from the Articles of Colonization
所有记录
to Zarek's trial record.
你们不得已删除了计算机驱动器里的信息 是吧?
You did have to erase your computer memory drives, correct?
是的
Yes, we did.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢凯恩上将
Thank Admiral Cain.
里面有没有色情内容?
Got any porn in there?
现在所有船只口粮减半
I've got ships on half-rations,
还有很多出现机械故障
and others experiencing mechanical difficulties.
目前只有卡拉狄加得到了所有的补给
And so far Galactica is the only vessel having any of its needs met.
因为军事行动的原因
Pegasus has been resupplying Galactica from it's own reserve
帕伽索斯一直在用自身的储备对卡拉狄加补给
for military operations.
这我完全支持
Which I completely support.
可什么时候能把其中一些补给品发放到舰队里?
But when will some of these supplies start getting out to the Fleet?
凯恩上将已向我保证
Admiral Cain has assured me
这些补给品正运往这里
that those supplies are on their way.
至少她还接你的电话
Well, at least she's taking your phone calls.
我就没那么幸运了
I can't even get her to answer mine.
我会和她说的
I'll bring it to her attention.
你怎么看待这些事的?
How are you doing with all this?
她比我的官大
She outranks me.
就这么简单
It's as simple as that.
如果是阿达尔总统从猛禽号走下来 我可就欣喜若狂了
You know, if President Adar stepped off that Raptor, I'd be elated.
感谢有人来接替这一切  然而…
Grateful to have someone take over. And yet...
我不想谈"然而"怎么样
I don't want to go to the "and yet" part.
我一生都听人差遣
I've been taking orders my entire career.
这次也没有例外
This is no different.
好吧 指挥官 谢谢
Well, then, Commander, thank you.
先感谢你为我们提供的帮助
We would appreciate all the help you can give us.
你会得到补给的
You shall receive it.
25号光电能量转换器
Twenty-five opto-electronic transducers.
好个"恐龙"宝宝
That's one ugly baby.
什么?
Excuse me?
我可以到处看看么?
Do you mind if I take a look around? I'm...
我是拉尔德  帕伽索斯的上士
I'm Laird, Pegasus Deck Chief.
恩  我是蒂罗尔
Oh, hey. Yeah. Tyrol.
多谢你们送来这些零配件
Thanks for sending over these parts.
请随便看
Yeah, look at whatever you like.
凯莉技师    你好
Specialist Cally. Hi.
DDG-62型
DDG-62's. I'll be...
我设计的这些引擎 我以为它们10年前就被淘汰了
I designed these engines. I thought they phased them out over 10 years ago.
你是航空工程师?
You're an aeronautical engineer?
曾经是
Yeah, I was.
然后开战了 我就被征回来当了帕伽索斯上的上士
Then the war happened, and I got drafted to being the Deck Chief on Pegasus.
那其实你是个平民? 怎么搞的?
So you're really a civilian? How'd that happen?
我当时在斯库拉  被帕伽索斯接走了
I was on the Scylla, and we got picked up by the Pegasus.
有时候就是那么巧
Things happen.
我爬到这里面去可以么?  我听说是你亲自设计的
Mind if I crawl around inside here? I heard you designed this yourself.
我想看看你怎么做的
I'd love to see how you did it.
当然了 请便
Sure, yeah. You'll get dirty.
有人来看我的船了
People come to see my ship.
别靠得太近 它已经杀了我的7名船员了
Don't get too close. It killed seven of my crew.
要我的守卫和你一起进去么?
You want my guards to come in with you?
害怕了  盖尤斯?
Feeling scared, Gaius?
想让傻大兵来保护你免遭凶狠的赛昂囚犯的毒手么?
Want the big, bad soldiers to protect you from the mean old Cylon prisoner?
不  没事  谢谢
No, I think we'll be just fine. Thank you.
我的天
Oh, my God.
我的天  盖尤斯
NO. 6: My God, Gaius.
那是我
It's me.
他们对她做了什么?
Look what they've done to her.
请快开门
Open the door. Now, please.
身份识别 索恩中尉
COMPUTER: ID confirmed. Lieutenant Thorne.
她肯定挣扎过
She must've struggled.
肯定反抗过
She must have fought back.
那也不能为这一切做辩护    住口
That doesn't justify this. Stop it.
喂
Hello.
喂  能听到我说话么?
Hello. Can you hear me?
她明显被虐待过
She's obviously been abused.
被折磨过    恩
Tortured. Yes.
没有明显的头部损伤
But there's no obvious sign of head trauma.
哦
Oh.
自主的眼部运动表明还有知觉
Voluntary eye movements suggest conscious thought.
你能不能少当会科学家?
Can't you stop being a scientist for one moment
看看躺在你面前这个遭受虐待的女人
and look at the abused woman lying there in front of you?
听我说
Now, listen up.
我知道你肯定很难受
I know this must be very difficult for you.
别照顾我
Don't patronize me.
我没照顾你  我要劝你(冷静)
I'm not patronizing you. I'm trying to reason with you.
如果要我帮她  就要先了解她的状况
If I'm going to help her, I have to understand her first.
你会帮她吗  盖尤斯?
Will you help her, Gaius?
我会竭尽所能的
I will do everything I can.
毕竟...
After all
她和我非常喜欢的一个女人有着惊人的相似
she is remarkably similar to someone I care about a great deal.
我想如果你能让我们独处一会...
I think it would be best
那再好不过了
if you left us alone for a time.
为了便于我的手段奏效
BALTAR: In order for my technique to work,
这方法已成功用于
the technique I used so successfully
自称为莎伦 卧莱瑞的赛昂人身上
on the Cylon who called herself Sharon Valerii,
必须允许那个犯人洗澡
the prisoner must be allowed to bathe adequately
和用食
and eat.
如果可以提供适当的衣物
If proper clothes could be provided and
以及其他的便利
other sundry comforts,
那就再好不过了
then that would be ideal.
我对这东西舒适与否毫无兴趣
The comfort of that thing is of no interest to me.
它害死了我舰队里800多人
It killed over 800 members of my crew.
恕我冒昧 上将
If you'll permit me, Admiral,
据我所知 它将一大堆病毒
as I understand it, it allowed a group of centurions
侵入了您的战舰系统  但它自身并未…
to board your ship, but it itself did not commit...
你是在为它开脱吗 博士?
Are you making excuses for it, Doctor?
你是否和实验目标靠的太近了?
Have you become too close to your subjects?
或许失去了判断力?
Lost perspective perhaps?
当然不是
Quite the opposite.
赛昂人是凶残的死敌
The Cylons are a brutal and deadly opponent,
如果它们被彻底消灭
the universe would be a substantially better place
整个宇宙将更太平
if they were exterminated entirely.
但我的工作不是杀戮
But my job is not extermination.
而是研究
My job is investigation.
看起来你似乎不是很在行
It doesn't sound like you're very good at it.
你没告知我任何有用的信息
You haven't told me anything new.
它没有严重的头部损伤
It suffered no serious head injuries,
因此对视神经通路
and therefore no physical damage
或认知推理中枢 没有物理性的伤害
to its neural pathways or cognitive reasoning centers.
但它显然受了精神创伤
But it's quite clearly traumatized.
也就表明它当前情况实质上是精神上的现象
Which would suggest that its current condition is psychological in nature.
这你想过么?  没有
Had you thought of that? No.
这说明赛昂人的精神在同样的压力情况下
It shows that the Cylon consciousness is just as susceptible
和人类的心理一样也容易受到影响产生裂痕
to the same pressures and cleavages as the human psyche
同样也可以被人操纵
and can be manipulated in the same fashion.
简单地说  上将  你已经威逼过了
Simply put, Admiral, you have already used the stick.
现在该利诱了
It's time to use a carrot.
请满足博士的一切需要
Please give the doctor whatever he needs.
是  长官
Aye, sir.
副总统先生 请跟我来
Mr. Vice President, if you'd follow me, please.
请
Sir.
很不错的船    多谢
Lovely ship. Thank you, sir.
看起来很新    是的
Looks very new. Yes, sir.
抱歉让你久等 指挥官
Sorry to keep you waiting, Commander.
而且没有地方让你坐
And that I can't offer you a place to sit.
我一直喜欢站着工作
I've always preferred to work standing up.
让我更容易保持清醒
It's much easier on my back.
我还发现站着工作
And I discovered meetings with my officers
能让军官们集合时更快到达
go faster when they have to stand as well,
所以椅子都被撤除了
so, out went the chairs.
我得记住这点
I'll have to remember that.
你有没有在船上看看?
Did you get a chance to look around the ship?
看了点
A little.
我有段时间没到过水星级战舰了
It's been a while since I've been on a Mercury class.
给作战信息中心
To CIC.
战舰规模是2倍 需要人手减半
Ship's nearly twice the size, needs half the crew.
让我感觉卡拉狄加是淘汰品
Makes me feel the Galactica is a relic.
卡拉狄加不是淘汰品 是经典
Galactica is not a relic. It's a classic.
我很欣赏经典
And I, for one, happen to appreciate the classics.
我注意到了
I've noticed.
你收藏了不少漂亮的武器
You have some beautiful weapons.
指挥官  我已经读了你的日志
Commander, having reviewed your logs,
看来你经历了好一场痛苦考验
it appears that you've been through quite an ordeal.
我们有过危急时刻
We've had our moments.
你应该为自己感到骄傲
You did yourselves proud.
谢谢  上将
Thank you, Admiral.
正如我告诉你的 我们发现卡拉狄加时 正在追踪一支赛昂舰队
As I told you, we were tracking a Cylon Fleet when we found Galactica.
现在我有机会拿他们的航线 和你们的飞船日志进行对比了
And now that I've had a chance to compare their route to your ship's logs,
显而易见  他们在跟踪你们
it's quite clear that they've been following you.
我们目前的侦察情报显示...
Our recon so far tells us
那支舰队由两艘基地飞船
that the fleet is composed of two Base Ships,
外加大约一打多的补给船组成
about a dozen or so support ships,
还有一艘我们仍旧无法确定的大型飞船
and one large vessel that we are still unable to identify.
我所感兴趣的就是这艘大型飞船
It's this large ship here that I'm interested in.
它有什么功能?  是一艘指挥舰?
What's its function? Is it a command and control ship?
突袭机制造厂?
A Raider factory?
有可能  无论是什么 赛昂人都在保护它
Possibly. Whatever it is, the Cylons are protecting it.
这就是我所说的诱饵
This is what I'd call a tempting target.
为了实施联合攻击计划
And here I was getting ready to do a whole song and dance
我可准备好大张旗鼓地合并资源了
about combining resources for a joint strike mission.
只要有机会打到赛昂人的痛处...
Any chance of hitting the Cylons where it hurts,
就是我的荣幸
my pleasure.
我会派阿波罗与你的空军指挥官合作的
I'll have Apollo coordinate with your CAG.
由此我们也就转到了另一个话题上  指挥官
Which leads me to the next subject, Commander.
我要合并船员
I'm going to integrate the crews.
把阿达玛上尉重新分配到帕伽索斯空军就是开始
And I'm starting by reassigning Captain Adama to the Pegasus air wing.
我有一支配合默契的团队
I have a team that works very well together.
我们就开门见山吧  好么?
Let's just cut through it, shall we?
在检查过你的日志之后...
After reviewing your logs, it is my judgment
我认为让你的儿子作为卡拉狄加空军指挥官是个严重的错误
that having your son as Galactica CAG has been a grave mistake.
他不服从上级 甚至还叛变
He's been insubordinate, even mutinous.
顺便说一句  这些还是你的日志里说的原话
And these are direct quotes from your logs, by the way.
我敢说不光就他有纪律问题
And I dare say, he's not the only one with disciplinary problems.
卡拉·瑟瑞丝经常殴打上级  违抗命令
There's a Kara Thrace who habitually strikes fellow officers and disobeys orders
这个阿格森中尉与…
This Lieutenant Agathon has fraternized with
明显怀有身孕的敌方密探关系暧昧
and evidently impregnated an enemy agent.
我们就别讨论副长了
Let's not even discuss your XO.
因此...
So,
这是一张完整的调任名单
there is a complete list of the transfers.
我记得你说过你无意介入我的指挥
I thought you said you had no desire to interfere with my command.
我在挽救你的指挥权  比尔
I'm saving your command, Bill.
你与这些军官太亲近了
You're way too close to these officers.
蒙蔽了他们的软弱
And it's blinding you to their weaknesses
以及他们对部队凝聚力和士气所造成的危害
and to the damage that they're doing to unit cohesion and to morale.
我不同意
I don't agree.
当然这是你的权利
Well, that is certainly your right.
执行命令吧
You have your orders.
调任到帕伽索斯?
Transfer to Pegasus?
妈的为什么要我们那么做?
Why the frak should we do that?
因为那是给你们的命令
Because those are your orders.
我们不能让她指手画脚    这是一派胡言
We can't just let her come over here That's a load of crap.
随意改变人员编制    她要分裂我们
and change our entire roster She's trying to break up the team
赛昂的大行动迫在眉睫
on the eve before a major Cylon operation.
因为他们空军指挥官的无能...        够了!
'cause their CAG has a stick up his ass... That's enough!
你们是军官  像个军官的样子!
You're officers. Act like it.
她对你们下了命令 你们就要去执行
She's given you an order. You will carry it out.
允许我随便说一句…    不行
Permission to speak freely? You may not.
我们都要习惯于屈从命令  自作主张...
We've all gotten used to bending the rules, having our way,
想干什么就干什么 那样的日子已经结束了
letting things slide. Well, that's over.
你们身着军装 就要遵守命令  听从指挥
You wear the uniform, you will accept the rules that go with it.
你们被调任了
You've been transferred.
整理好装备到帕伽索斯的空军指挥官那里报道
Pack your gear and report to the Pegasus CAG.
星芭儿
Starbuck.
自己小心
Watch out for yourselves.
我想他们是针对你们俩的
I think they're gunning for you both.
我想是针对我们所有人
I think they're gunning for all of us.
你好    你好
Hey. Hey.
你的方法提升了百分之二的燃料效率
You know, that idea you had increased fuel efficiency by two percent.
很高兴能帮上忙
I'm glad I could help out.
这是狗屁  上士
This is bullshit, Chief.
为什么大家都怒气冲冲
Why is everyone so pissed off?
哦 我们才听说…
Oh, we just heard
有个帕伽索斯来的王八蛋要接管我的甲板
brass is bringing over some frakwit from the Pegasus to take over my deck.
这很让人气愤…
That's... That's gotta burn.
对
Yeah.
我就是那个王八蛋 抱歉
I'm the frakwit. Sorry.
办公室在这后面
Office is back here.
这是一项侦察拍照任务
This is a photo recon mission.
我们尤其对一艘赛昂飞船有兴趣
We're interested in one Cylon ship in particular
它比我们至今遇到的飞船都更庞大
which is larger than anything we've encountered before.
日常分析显示他们下次会到我们所在的星系
Analysis to date suggests they will be in this star system next.
我们将躲在这个卫星后面
We will hide behind this moon
它具有异常巨大磁尾
which has an abnormally large magnetotail
可以屏蔽雷达信号
and will mask our dradis signatures.
我们将减小推进力  贴近表面
We'll power down, hide near the surface,
等待舰队经过
wait for the fleet to pass by.
星芭儿?    嗯?
Starbuck? Yeah?
你要补充几句么?
You've something to add?
你的计划真差劲
Your plan sucks.
你第一天来就口出狂言啊
You're a heartbeat away from being in hack on your first day.
我喜欢口出狂言
I like hack.
很好
It's good to know.
赛昂人又不傻
And the Cylons aren't stupid.
那卫星是个盲点  他们才不会靠近它
That moon's a blind spot. They'll never go near it.
你真想靠近他们...
You really wanna get close,
就要用
you gotta use the stealth ship
我们在卡拉狄加上造的隐形飞船
we constructed aboard Galactica.
自制罐头?
The homemade tin can?
够了
TAYLOR: That's enough.
星芭儿  你不用参与这次任务了
Starbuck, you're off this mission.
韦普莱士  萨普尔 准备好你们的光学设备
Whiplash, Thumper, get your optical gear ready.
阿波罗  你和我驾驶猛禽飞船
Apollo, you'll pilot the Raptor with me.
你的外套说明你够资格
Your jacket says you qualified in one.
还记得怎么驾驶么?
Remember how to fly it?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
好
Good.
立正
On your feet.
解散
Dismissed.
他们想让我对这件事逆来顺受?
They expect us to take this lying down?
现在你变成开猛禽号的了  真丢人
Now you're flying a frakking Raptor? It's humiliating.
监视装备?
A surveillance package?
去开黑鸟  照几张赛昂基地飞船的漂亮图片
Go get the Blackbird. Take some pretty pictures of our Cylon ship.
收到
Copy that.
大家干杯!        干杯
Cheers, everybody. ALL: Cheers!
那架黑鸟在那里?        瑟瑞丝中尉开出去了
Where's the Blackbird? Lieutenant Thrace took it out.
她说凯恩上将下令表演一下
She said Admiral Cain ordered a performance check out.
什么?        上士
What? GAGE: Hey, Chief.
你该获得一枚他妈的勋章 我们都几个月没喝酒了
You deserve a frakking medal. We haven't seen booze for months.
这地方真他妈的是个派对
This place is a frakking party!
我听说你们甚至都找了一个赛昂人
VIREEM: Oh, I heard you guys even got yourselves a Cylon.
听说她还很火辣
Heard she's a hot one, too.
我也许还能和赛昂人搞搞 是吧?
I'd like to get me some of that Cylon stuff, huh?
一点点嘿咻嘿咻
A little of the, "Oh, yeah, oh, yeah. "
好了  够了  两位  闭嘴吧
Hey, you know what, that's enough, guys. Just shut up.
敏感呐  你对那机器小妞心软  是吧?
Sensitive. You got a soft spot for the little robot girl, do you?
嗨 上士说了闭嘴 你没听见
Hey. Chief said to shut up. Maybe you didn't hear him.
对不起 长官
Hey. Sorry, sir.
听着 我们只是来找点乐子 好吗
Look, we're just here for a little fun, huh?
干杯
Cheers.
拜托 来吧
Come on. There we go.
你们究竟是谁?
Who the hell are you?
你还记得桑恩
Remember, remember, when Thorne put
把那个"请打扰"的牌子挂在禁闭室外么?
that "please disturb" sign up on the brig there?
我赶上了两次    我听说了
I got in line twice. Oh, I hear that.
还记得她就躺在那里  脸色苍白
Remember she was just lying there with that blank look on her face, like...
你们注意点行么?
Hey, do you mind?
哦 跳起来了
Ooh, frisky.
生气了
That hurts.
这艘船有什么功能?
What is the function of this ship?
不知道    给  仔细看看
I don't know. Here, take a closer look.
为什么它显得那么重要?
What makes it so important?
为什么要派两艘基地之星专门保护它?
Why would two Base Stars be tasked to protect it?
不  不知...
I don't...
不知道
I don't know.
你说桑恩这次也会给我们个机会么?
Do you think Thorne will give us a chance at this one, too?
不  我听他说他要先给她尝点苦头
No, I heard him say he's gonna have to break her in a little first.
不  不  别在这里
Hey, whoa, whoa. I know, but not here.
这个桑恩到底谁?
Who the hell's this Thorne?
桑恩中尉  长官  赛昂审讯官
Lieutenant Thorne, sir. Cylon interrogator.
"骑"上她们  她们才招
Rides them hard and keeps them talking.
你的机器小妞要当坐骑了
Your little robot girl is in for quite a ride.
嘻嗨
Hee-haw.
想清楚了  我们得走了
Think about it. We need to go.
怎么他妈回事?
What the frak?
好吧    不！
Okay. No!
我会说的
I'll tell you!
快走  别挡道!
Move it! Get out of the way!
快快快！ 让路
Move, move, move, move! Get... Get out of the way!
快 快
Move, move!
救命  救命
Help! Help!
放开她!
TYROL: Get off of her!
立刻放开她!
Get off of her, now!
妈的
Motherfrakker!
住手  住手
GAURD: Freeze! Freeze!
不许动!你们两个都他妈的别动!
Don't either of you frakking move! Don't move!
都他妈的别动!
Don't either of you frakking move!
别动!
Don't move!
蹲下!蹲下!
Get down! Get down!
跪下!
On your knees.
把手放在头后!  快!
Hands behind your head. Now!
把手放在头后!
GAURD 2: Hands behind your head.
快!  快!
Do it now. Do it!
他死了
GUARD 1: He's dead.
帕伽索斯  我是猛禽923号  我们已从卡拉狄加出发
PILOT 1: Pegasus, Raptor 923. We've cleared Galactica
带着犯人和桑恩中尉的尸体
and are en route with prisoners and the body of Lieutenant Thorne.
预计3分钟内到达帕伽索斯
PILOT 2: ETA to Pegasus, three minutes.
袭击是在这里发生的
ADAMA: The assault happened here.
他们应该在卡拉狄加上面对军事法庭的审判
They should face a court martial on Galactica.
指挥官  我当前具有高级传唤权
Commander, I am the senior convening authority present.
他们将在帕伽索斯上接受审判
And they'll be tried on Pegasus.
他们是我的人  我的一个人已经死了
They're my men. One of my men is dead.
好吧  我们都对这件事都很激动
Fine. We both have strong feelings about the case.
重要的是要有公正的审判
That only underlines the need for an impartial trial.
你是说独立仲裁庭?
Oh, you mean an independent tribunal?
因为根据你的日志上所说  指挥官
Because according to your logs, Commander,
当你不喜欢判决结果的时候 就解散了一个独立仲裁庭
you dissolved an independent tribunal when you didn't like the verdict.
如果我没说错的话 蒂罗尔上士那次也曾受过审讯
And if I'm not mistaken, Chief Tyrol was on trial there as well.
那次是不同时期
That was a different time.
是的  确实如此
Yes, indeed it was.
随时保持联络  指挥官  多谢
I'll be in touch, Commander. Thank you.
请解开镣铐 谢谢
Remove the restraints, please.
是上将授权我来这里的
I'm here under Admiral Cain's authority.
听我的
Do it.
谢谢  现在出去吧
Thank you. Now, get out.
食物是为你准备的
The food is yours.
不是恶作剧
It's not a trick.
我不会在最后时刻拿走
I'm not gonna take it away at the last second.
我...
You know, I...
那我现在就开始说了
I'm just going to talk right now.
你不用说什么
I don't expect you to say anything.
在卡布里卡的时候  在袭击之前...
Back on Caprica, before the attack...
有时候...
And sometimes
我都忘了在袭击之前那里还有一个世界
I forget there was a world before the attack.
我认识一个人  一个女人
I knew someone, a woman,
不像我所认识的其他女人
unlike any other woman I'd ever known.
她是独一无二的
She was unique.
美丽  聪慧
Beautiful. Clever.
流连于肉欲
Intensely sensual.
当她不在我床上的时候
When she wasn't in my bed,
我就挂念她
she was in my thoughts.
她是一个赛昂人
She was a Cylon.
她用最真实  最基本的方式改变了我的生活
And she changed my life in a very real, very fundamental way,
我无时无刻不在想着她
in that I have quite literally never stopped thinking about her.
因为我爱她
Because I love her.
时至今日  我仍旧爱她
To this very day, I love her.
她看起来和一模一样
And she looks exactly like you.
我叫盖尤斯·波塔尔
My name is Gaius Baltar.
我是来这里帮助你的
And I'm here to help you.
帮我检查一下这些跳跃坐标
Check me on these jump coordinates.
阿波罗
Apollo.
帮我检查一下这些跳跃坐标
Check me on these jump coordinates.
不好意思
Sorry.
跳跃坐标验证完毕
Jump coordinates verified.
看来你有些心不在焉  上尉
You seem a little distracted, Captain.
有什么事能对我说一下么?
Something I should know about?
我的两个朋友因叛国罪被抓了起来
Two of my friends just got arrested and charged with treason.
我建议你把这当作"不关你的事"处理
I suggest you file that under "not your problem. "
我们还要进行侦察任务 我需要你全神贯注
We have a recon mission to perform. I need your head in the game.
好
Right.
帕伽索斯  我是蓝队  跳跃坐标设置验证完毕
Pegasus, Blue Team, jump coordinates set and verified.
准备超光速跳跃 我们将在10分钟内跳跃
Ready to FTL. We will jump in 10 minutes
按我口令计时      开始
on my mark. Mark.
有上士的消息么  长官?
Any word on the Chief, sir?
他不得不受审
He's gonna have to stand trial.
他是好人  长官
He's a good man, sir.
我知道  我会尽全力…    注意 卡拉狄加
I know. I'll do every... MAN:Attention, Galactica.
阿达玛指挥官 请速给作战信息中心回话
...Commander Adama, contact the CIC ASAP.
我是阿达玛
Adama.
我刚和费斯科通过话  军事法庭已经结束了
I just talked to Fisk. Court martial's over.
结束了?  什么时候开始的?
Over? When did it start?
不知道  但各方面都判定他们有罪
I don't know, but they've been found guilty on all counts.
她要以谋杀和叛国两项罪名处决他们
She's going to execute them both for murder and treason.
5分钟内准备好一支陆战队攻击小组 登上一架猛禽号上
I want a Marine strike team in a Raptor in five minutes.
准备好发射待战机
Prepare to launch alert fighters.
有活要干了    是  长官
We have work to do. Sir.
帕伽索斯  这里是卡拉狄加 请打开一个频道
WOMAN:Pegasus, Galactica. Please secure channel.
阿达玛指挥官想和凯恩上将通话
Commander Adama would like to speak to Admiral Cain.
请说吧  长官
DUALLA: Go ahead, sir.
你对我说他们会得到一个公正的判决
You told me they'd get a fair trial.
他们可能会得到什么样的判决?
What kind of a trial could they have possibly had?
我可以向你保证我听过了他们的证词
CAIN: I assure you, I heard them out.
我权衡了他们与守卫相反的证词
I weighed their statements against those of the guards
并就他们的服役记录以及所获的荣誉仔细考虑过了
and I took into consideration their service records and commendations.
这是一个艰难的决定  指挥官 但我敢说是公正的
It was a difficult decision, Commander, but I dare say, it was a fair one.
他们有权利让陪审团听取他们的案子
They have the right to have their case heard by a jury.
我是战时特谴任务的舰队指挥官
I am a flag officer on detached service during a time of war.
在这件事情上规章给我充分的权利
Regulations give me broad authority in this matter.
发射战机
Launch the fighters.
你想引用什么规章制度来敷衍我都可以
You can quote me whatever regulation you'd like.
我不会让你处决我的人
I'm not gonna let you execute my men.
我强烈建议你重新考虑一下你所作的声明  指挥官
I highly suggest you reconsider that statement, Commander.
上将  卡拉狄加派出了蝮蛇战机和一架猛禽号
Admiral, Galactica is launching Vipers and a Raptor.
指挥官  为什么你要派出蝮蛇战机?
Commander, why are you launching Vipers?
在蒂罗尔上士和阿格森中尉到达后
Please arrange for Chief Tyrol and Lieutenant Agathon
请安排把他们尽快交给我们的陆战队
to be handed over to my Marines as soon as they arrive.
我不用听从你的命令
I don't take orders from you.
随便你怎么说  我要把我的人带回来
Call it whatever you like. I'm getting my men.
你犯了一个大错误
You are making such a mistake.
我要把我的人带回来
I'm getting my men.
各就各位
Action stations. Action stations.
上将  这将导致形势迅速恶化
Admiral, this will spiral out of control fast.
发射待战机
Launch the alert Vipers.
阿达玛逼我们走到了这一步
Adama has taken us over the line.
他没留给我们选择的余地 发射待战机
He's left me with no choice. Launch the alert Vipers.
目标卡拉狄加主炮
And target the main battery for Galactica.
愿上帝怜悯他们的灵魂
And may the Gods have mercy on their souls.